<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Me on Big Bag Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Me on Big Bag Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Bed Ideas</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/04/18/ghost-bed-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/04/18/ghost-bed-ideas/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;those-thoughts-that-crawl-around-at-midnight:09323e6b5e851f2e0b79c1b560fadfa2&#34;&gt;Those thoughts that crawl around at midnight.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was talking about ideas last week and suddenly I realised that my ideas don&amp;#8217;t come from nothing but from a seed idea. Something that makes an impact or attracts my mind somehow triggers the idea generation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is more or less like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I see something I like, for example, the stool that rocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That sensation/memory lingers in y head for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start spawning random thoughts of how I would do if I were or what I would do if I could&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of side jumping between ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you seen how designers work? designers produce and discard an extraordinary amount of work. My idea generation process is a bit like that. Hammering the concept with as many random thoughts as possible and looking at how the idea shapes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, using the stool that rocks I could talk about the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Ghost Bed Idea&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; which is nothing more that a design of a bed I&amp;#8217;ve made based on the principles of the stool that rocks: that you can make your own furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But can you? Can you really make your own table? bed? chairs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t see why not. Unfortunately for me, my cad skills are almost none, but I know how to draw, and yes I know how to do technical drawing too&amp;#8230; and I&amp;#8217;m not engineer but I know enough of tensions, forces and resistance to think of what it means to build something like a bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to imagine my wife&amp;#8217;s reaction next time she ask me what I&amp;#8217;m doing: &amp;#8220;Actually, a bed, darling&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;#8217;s face it. For now, it&amp;#8217;s more a concept, a few sketches and some random queries in google to find out how thick wood has to be to be able to build a bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ghost-bed.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-114&#34; alt=&#34;ghost bed&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ghost-bed-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Apps, a workshop</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/06/mobile-apps-a-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/06/mobile-apps-a-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I will be giving a workshop about Mobile Apps to the fine people of QME (Queen Mary Entrepreneurs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop will be focused mainly on planning and designing the app. I think we&amp;#8217;ll have to leave the building part for a second part, follow up, or call it as you want, but if we can leave with a clear idea of what the app has to do it will be a success from my part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, me being me, I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten half of the stuff I wanted to bring and perhaps I should take my lunch and go home to get all the material. Nothing fancy, post-it notes, pencils, and my video adaptor for my laptop O_0 &amp;lt;&amp;#8211; don&amp;#8217;t panic, I have my good old Mac with me, so we&amp;#8217;re safe  &lt;img src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif&#34; alt=&#34;:)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; /&gt;and yes, a quick trip to Rymans can sort the stationery out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why? really, why?</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/05/why-really-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/05/why-really-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me put it like this&amp;#8230; I stop writing ages ago because I could not find where to do it. I&amp;#8217;ve really tried to write in all the blogs of all my failed projects (and there&amp;#8217;re a few) but I&amp;#8217;ve failed (once more).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have returned to my old grabuma blog, but alas, I wanted something more&amp;#8230; not sure, but going back to blogger seemed wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been willing to write about several things but I couldn&amp;#8217;t find the place. I even consider the fact of writing yet-another-blogging system&amp;#8230; Enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give me a notebook and my pen: I have to write a bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>