<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats on Big Bag Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/tags/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stats on Big Bag Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pedrazas.me/tags/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret Valentine – Results</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/20/secret-valentine-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/20/secret-valentine-results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost a week ago and I&amp;#8217;ve said a word about My Secret Valentine project&amp;#8230; yet. you will have to excuse me but I&amp;#8217;ve been a bit busy. Things of having to deal with children during Half Term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s get into the story. Last week I published a very little app that the only thing that did was to send a (not very pretty, have to reckon) message and a picture by email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total numbers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;30 installations in 7 countries (UK, Spain, USA, Ireland, Netherlands, Panama, Ukraine)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;89 Valentines sent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 Uninstalls (after 14th of February)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;78 visits to the app page (78.71% from Twitter, 8.17% from Facebook, 0% from G+).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://karmacracy.com/&#34;&gt;Karmacrazy&lt;/a&gt; to check how many people went to the Play page. In case you don&amp;#8217;t know, Google doesn&amp;#8217;t let you track how many people visit your app&amp;#8217;s page. But as I said, no analytics? no problem. In fact, you can take a look to the link stats to see the kind of information you can get from this tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to give it a go, use this &lt;a href=&#34;http://kcy.me/fo6q&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More numbers. Android Versions. And this is kind of a surprise, because in the last Droidcon we talked loooong time about legacy android versions and here we have the proof of what&amp;#8217;s the biggest problem with Android so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/stats-msv.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-52&#34; alt=&#34;stats-msv&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/stats-msv.png&#34; width=&#34;985&#34; height=&#34;364&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As you can see the top version is the very old 2.3.x followed by all the 4s. I fact, if we unify all the Jelly Bean devices we see that 75% of the devices are running Jelly Bean. However, who&amp;#8217;s going to shut the door to 30% of their potential customers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are prone to slag Android think about it. Updates don&amp;#8217;t come from Google, updates come from your carriers. The more the Android device has been customised, the harder it will be to update. Why so many devices still on 2.3.x ? because of the 24m contracts, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>