<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tomcat on Big Bag Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/tags/tomcat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tomcat on Big Bag Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pedrazas.me/tags/tomcat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>(Gunicorn &#43; Python) vs (Tomcat &#43; Java)</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/06/12/gunicorn-python-vs-tomcat-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/06/12/gunicorn-python-vs-tomcat-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing an app it&amp;#8217;s one thing, deploying an app it&amp;#8217;s a very different matter. Last night we were discussing about the differences between deploying Java apps and deploying python apps. I must admit that I never put my head to look at how python apps were deployed, so this morning I decided to take a look and&amp;#8230; yes, deploying a java app in Tomcat is still easier than deploying a python app with gunicorn (let the troll wars begin!). True, to deploy an app with gunicorn you just need this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;gunicorn --log-level=debug -c gunicorn.conf hello:app&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or if just &amp;#8220;gunicorn hello:app&amp;#8221; which is great, it couldn&amp;#8217;t be more simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&amp;#8230; Imagine this scenario: we create 2 apps, one in Java, one in python, let&amp;#8217;s say, using Flask (I could have said Django&amp;#8230; but let&amp;#8217;s keep it simple).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have my BIG FAT SERVER where I have my tomcat instance and my gunicorn instance running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To deploy the java app I need to create a war file and upload it using the admin page&amp;#8230; et voila, we have java app deployed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To deploy the python app I need to ssh to that server, scp the python app files over, and run that line from above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair enough, it&amp;#8217;s not that different and gunicorn kicks ass, but let&amp;#8217;s be honest here, even if we had to ssh and copy over the war file&amp;#8230; just by putting it in the right directory it will self-deploy. Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong, I do love python and when I can, I much rather use python-gunicorn than any of their java cousins, but we have to be fair with the fat jvm relatives, haven&amp;#8217;t we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, Java wins!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>