<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Children on Big Bag Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/children/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Children on Big Bag Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/children/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Breeding Entrepreneurs</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/03/26/breading-entrepreneurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/03/26/breading-entrepreneurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t usually talk about my children unless you&amp;#8217;re a close friend. However, today I&amp;#8217;m going to do an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My oldest son is 11. I guess I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who worries and wonders what will happen with his children when they grow up and have to face reality. Have my wife and I done a good job and prepare themselves to find their own way in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions, many questions&amp;#8230; and finally, one answer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought a 3D printer. I&amp;#8217;m a developer with -3 skills in 3D design&amp;#8230; or almost any design, so there&amp;#8217;s no way I can justify that the printer was a &amp;#8220;work related&amp;#8221; purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I love making things. The fact that at work people refers to me as the guy to fetch if you want things done will give you the insight that I will not sit idle in my chair&amp;#8230; or any chair.[I don&amp;#8217;t usually talk about my children unless you&amp;#8217;re a close friend. However, today I&amp;#8217;m going to do an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My oldest son is 11. I guess I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who worries and wonders what will happen with his children when they grow up and have to face reality. Have my wife and I done a good job and prepare themselves to find their own way in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions, many questions&amp;#8230; and finally, one answer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought a 3D printer. I&amp;#8217;m a developer with -3 skills in 3D design&amp;#8230; or almost any design, so there&amp;#8217;s no way I can justify that the printer was a &amp;#8220;work related&amp;#8221; purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I love making things. The fact that at work people refers to me as the guy to fetch if you want things done will give you the insight that I will not sit idle in my chair&amp;#8230; or any chair.]&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/photo-1.jpg&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not talk about 3D printing here, I will talk about a side effect of having a 3D printer at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My children sees the printer as a wonderful toy generator machine&amp;#8230; and I have to recognise that the little people have veritable passion for the plastic moulded stuff: look at their toys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to the point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my boy came to me with a list. He was looking at the list and mumbling some words when I asked what was the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/photo-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-200&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/photo-1-225x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;He showed me that list. It was a list of names and words and numbers that made no sense at the beginning&amp;#8230; then he explained his business idea to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m going to sell toys at school, dad&amp;#8230; and this is the list of the people who wants to buy things from me&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the odd list made sense:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the name of a child, the name of the toys and the price they had to pay for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m going to get rich selling toys, dad&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smiled and asked him if he had considered how much it cost to produce the toys and he looked at me puzzled:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s free, dad!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well, the fact that you don&amp;#8217;t pay anything it doesn&amp;#8217;t mean it&amp;#8217;s free&amp;#8221; (my mind drifted to all this web services that were supposedly free in exchange of &amp;#8220;some&amp;#8221; of your data&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/minion.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-205&#34; alt=&#34;minion&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/minion-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to explain to him how he could calculate and how much he should charge for every toy&amp;#8230; I could see he lost interest quickly &amp;#8220;makes no sense, dad&amp;#8230; I cannot put a different price to any toy, I will need two lists, one for my toys and one for the children&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed you will need, my dear&amp;#8230; That&amp;#8217;s exactly how shops all over the world work. You have a list with stock and prices and a list of customers&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversation moved on and we left the little toy factory aside but when I went to bed I told my wife &amp;#8220;darling, I&amp;#8217;m afraid we&amp;#8217;re breeding Entrepreneurs&amp;#8221; and last night, last night I slept well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Challenge</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/06/30/the-challenge-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/06/30/the-challenge-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently me and my wife have been having some problems with Internet and Children. I know, there are hundreds of filters and ways of preventing children to access content that it not appropriate to their age&amp;#8230; and none seems to work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can enable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/preferences&#34;&gt;Safe Search&lt;/a&gt; in Google and YouTube Safety Mode. Let me show you acouple of Image Searches by Mighty Google with the Safe Search On, I searched for &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.uk/search?hl=en&amp;amp;authuser=0&amp;amp;site=imghp&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;source=hp&amp;amp;biw=1920&amp;amp;bih=990&amp;amp;q=human+rights&#34;&gt;Human Rights&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Selection_021.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-165&#34; alt=&#34;Google Search&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Selection_021-300x140.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;140&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Selection_020.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-164&#34; alt=&#34;Google Search&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Selection_020-300x151.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;151&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, yes, almost all the images are &amp;#8220;safe&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230; almost. Thing is, if you disable that safe search the results contain less blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other options are using a proxy that filters out the dodgy content but not many people know how to install those things that have evolved into add-ons or extensions that filter out certain pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue with those solutions is that you rely on a company that gathers your browsing data (and your children&amp;#8217;s browsing data) and all of them have long Terms and Conditions and what really worries me is that as a company, you need to make money. Since they give away their product, I&amp;#8217;m afraid that the real product is the user&amp;#8217;s data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as parents we have some options. But it&amp;#8217;s not what us as parents can do, but what our children are going to do. An example would be WoT, a great idea with a big problem: children don&amp;#8217;t understand it. WoT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;crowdsources ratings from a global community of millions of users, who rate and comment on websites based on their personal experiences&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wicked! Now when I search I see that little green/red icon next to the results&amp;#8230; Do you think that children understand that? me neither.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong, I think it is a great idea and it is the way to go. They have options to &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Block sites that are unsuitable for children&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;. So, in many ways it is better than using Mighty Google and its Safe Search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screenshot-from-2013-06-30-233411.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-167&#34; alt=&#34;WoT&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screenshot-from-2013-06-30-233411-300x267.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately WoT is not only focused on Children safety which is good and bad&amp;#8230; but it is a great idea and I will be looking at them (and their API) more closely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best Add-ons for Firefox or Chrome is Web Filter by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudacl.com/&#34;&gt;CloudAcl&lt;/a&gt;. It allows you Black List or White List websites. A parents/kids mode and it&amp;#8217;s password protected&amp;#8230; and they have a mobile version for your iPhone/iPad or your Android device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Selection_022.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-173&#34; alt=&#34;CloudAcl&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Selection_022-296x300.png&#34; width=&#34;296&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is to use a &amp;#8220;Kid&amp;#8217;s Safe Browser&amp;#8221; like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kidzui.com/&#34;&gt;KidZui&lt;/a&gt;. Again, this is a great tool with the only issue of why do they need to gather and keep browsing history in their servers and not keep it in MY BROWSER!!! (the fact that they do that is a big red flag, since technically there&amp;#8217;s no reason for taking my data somewhere else and by doing that your message is &amp;#8220;I do it because that&amp;#8217;s how I make money&amp;#8221;. Again, me and my children are the product not the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it seems, the options out there are not as good as we might expect. Or they are not as efficient as we would like to or they are not specialised in children&amp;#8217;s browing or they have a dodgy business model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;strong&gt;I would like&lt;/strong&gt; is to have an &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;open source solution&lt;/span&gt; that stops my children from seeing things that are not appropriate for them. I&amp;#8217;d like to have also a tool that allows me easily to monitor what is going on when I&amp;#8217;m not there browsing with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure if there&amp;#8217;s such thing, what I know is that I haven&amp;#8217;t found it yet&amp;#8230;  Since I like technology and specially &lt;a href=&#34;www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pis&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;m building a plug and play device that I call &lt;strong&gt;SafeBerry Pi&lt;/strong&gt; and it&amp;#8217;s basically the monitoring tool. Still very early stages but worry not, I will be writing about it as soon as I have something (stable) working, so, stay tunned!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not The Pizza Example… yet</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/04/07/not-the-pizza-example-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/04/07/not-the-pizza-example-yet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-explain-geeky-grown-up-things-to-children:b87417a3db83b0c819bd99e32e2357cb&#34;&gt;How to explain geeky grown up things to children&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times that you have to think fast. There are times you cannot think at all, like when my little boy asked me &amp;#8220;Dad, what is the Internet?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer then was not great, but I think I manage to send my message. It was something like &amp;#8220;Imagine that the game you play in internet were a building. Imagine as well that the web pages you visit are buildings as well. YouTube? like the cinemas at Wetsfields. yes? He nodded so I took it as if he was following me&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well, if you can see all those websites like buildings, Internet are the roads and streets that take you from one to another. Then you have search engines like Google that are like the tube, that will take you to that far building down there but faster. Do you understand?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;So&amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s not a place, it&amp;#8217;s the way you go from one place to another?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;yup&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Oh&amp;#8230; is it that why granddad calls it &lt;strong&gt;The Information Highway&lt;/strong&gt;?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#facepalm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time he asks me something like that I will direct him straight to my dad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>