<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats on Big Bag Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/stats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stats on Big Bag Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/stats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of traffic for My Secret Valentine</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/21/analysis-of-traffic-for-my-secret-valentine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/21/analysis-of-traffic-for-my-secret-valentine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post I gave a few figures about how many installations, messages, and more. Between all those numbers there was this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;78 visits to the app page (78.71% from Twitter, 8.17% from Facebook, 0% from G+)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this, my friends, it&amp;#8217;s why you all should have the best communicators driving your corporate twitter accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, let&amp;#8217;s be honest here. I really thought that Facebook would be 0 and that Google Plus would be closer to twitter&amp;#8230; and I was wrong. Very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google must be doing something very wrong to not driving traffic like that. 0%? that&amp;#8217;s absolute rubbish!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind that I posted to different G+ circles with, in total, thousands of people. Result: 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Facebook ONLY for family and close friends&amp;#8230; so, don&amp;#8217;t get offended if I don&amp;#8217;t know you very well and I don&amp;#8217;t accept your facebook request&amp;#8230; and now remember that me being Spanish and spaniards not mastering English it&amp;#8217;s kind of foreseeable that not much traffic will come from Facebook&amp;#8230; still, almost a 10% came from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me remind you that Thousands in G+ were trumped by a handful of Facebook friends, and completely smashed by Twitter. Google, you&amp;#8217;re doing something very wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did we say Twitter? well, I have less than 400 followers, but I managed to get 78 clicks. 72 of which came from Twitter&amp;#8230; So, 1 in 5 of my followers clicked my link. Will be good to know if this percentage scale but I&amp;#8217;m afraid it will not, still 20% of my followers visiting the app page is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from this? Twitter is a wicked for promotion. Forget Facebook, Ignore Google Plus. Tweet, Tweet, Tweet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone in the room fancy sharing their experiences?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>