<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Startups on Big Bag Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/startups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Startups on Big Bag Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.pedrazas.me/categories/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Enter Bitcoin</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/06/27/enter-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/06/27/enter-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/bitcoin-logo-1000_0.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-271&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/bitcoin-logo-1000_0-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bitcoin-logo-1000_0&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month I decided that it was time for Bitcoin and I to spend more quality time together. So I went to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.megamine.com/&#34;&gt;MegaMine&lt;/a&gt; and opened an account. Why Megamine and not some others? well, truth is that they are local. It&amp;#8217;s a Startup from London, you can go and visit them. Depending on the time of the day they will buy you a coffee or a beer and have a nice chat with you&amp;#8230; and yes, their prices are super competitive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bumped into them because I was looking for a cheap datacenter to host my machines to build my OpenStack Empire, but that&amp;#8217;s another story. Let&amp;#8217;s focus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get into Bitcoins there are two ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can mine Bitcoins, aka Bitcoin mining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can buy Bitcoins. In the same way that you would buy any other foreign currency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difference is the price. Buying Bitcoins is like buying US Dollars, or British Pounds. (Buying and selling prices are different.) When mining you pay for the usage of a mining machine (or a pool), regardless of the price of the Bitcoin (well, that&amp;#8217;s the theory). This means that under certain circumstances, buying Bitcoin is more convenient that mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;buying Bitcoin is not as straightforward as many people think. Yes, there are places where you can go and buy Bitcoins. for example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbargain.co.uk/buy&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;. Now, if you notice, the website does not sell Bitcoins, the website will allow you to buy Bitcoins (from someone else), and because of that, every transaction has different conditions (looks dodgy, doesn&amp;#8217;t it?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the month SatoshiPoint presented their machines and I rushed to go and compare what I could get from them compared to what I could get from mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference was that the machines will give you your bitcoin straightaway (in reality it the transaction took around 13 minutes to go through) compared to the 5~ish days that I had to spend mining to get the same amount of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I see it, if you want your Bitcoins now, go and buy them out of some place. Make sure the website is the one selling the Bitcoins and not-yet-another-middle-man-in-the-middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to squeeze your money and get a higher return&amp;#8230; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.megamine.com/pricing.php&#34;&gt;go and mine&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure if Megamine will sell Bitcoins in the future or not, but I will be asking them next time I see them for a coffee or a beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Mining!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;#8217;m not related to Megamine in any way nor they give me any satoshis to write about them (although any offered will be most welcome!).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Access</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/05/04/distributed-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/05/04/distributed-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sharing information is not easy. We are animals of customs. Moving from one way of doing things to another takes time and it creates friction and it happens, over time that we accept the new way of doing things as the &amp;#8220;way we do this&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with a distributed team is strange. my team is not exactly distributed, but asynchronous. Working with people whoe are not next to you creates a barrier, but opens up tons of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife recently asked  advise about how to deal with a distributed and/or asynchronous team. Technically we have so many options that it&amp;#8217;s difficult to know which is the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the applications that in my experience, make a distributed async team to be as productive as working together elbow to elbow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serialised Chat:&lt;/strong&gt; a chat where people can see the last 4 days of history. Chats are not only useful to &amp;#8220;chat&amp;#8221; but to keep track of what was going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Blogs:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the core of a team. Every single team should have an internal blog where they dump what&amp;#8217;s happening. I know, it seems the same than the chat, but it&amp;#8217;s not. Chats are prone to off topics and and are terriffic to let people know. Blogs allow transmitting info and gathering comments dead easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skype/hangouts:&lt;/strong&gt; not much to say here really. There are times that a simple phone call can sort out many problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wiki:&lt;/strong&gt; nothing beats the good old wiki to create a solid knowledge base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Github:&lt;/strong&gt; git it&amp;#8217;s not only great for code, but for anything you need to pull-request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropbox:&lt;/strong&gt; sharing made easy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have tried things like basecamp, yammer or jive and they are great but they do not fit very well with small teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breeding Entrepreneurs</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/03/26/breading-entrepreneurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2014/03/26/breading-entrepreneurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t usually talk about my children unless you&amp;#8217;re a close friend. However, today I&amp;#8217;m going to do an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My oldest son is 11. I guess I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who worries and wonders what will happen with his children when they grow up and have to face reality. Have my wife and I done a good job and prepare themselves to find their own way in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions, many questions&amp;#8230; and finally, one answer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought a 3D printer. I&amp;#8217;m a developer with -3 skills in 3D design&amp;#8230; or almost any design, so there&amp;#8217;s no way I can justify that the printer was a &amp;#8220;work related&amp;#8221; purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I love making things. The fact that at work people refers to me as the guy to fetch if you want things done will give you the insight that I will not sit idle in my chair&amp;#8230; or any chair.[I don&amp;#8217;t usually talk about my children unless you&amp;#8217;re a close friend. However, today I&amp;#8217;m going to do an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My oldest son is 11. I guess I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who worries and wonders what will happen with his children when they grow up and have to face reality. Have my wife and I done a good job and prepare themselves to find their own way in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions, many questions&amp;#8230; and finally, one answer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought a 3D printer. I&amp;#8217;m a developer with -3 skills in 3D design&amp;#8230; or almost any design, so there&amp;#8217;s no way I can justify that the printer was a &amp;#8220;work related&amp;#8221; purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I love making things. The fact that at work people refers to me as the guy to fetch if you want things done will give you the insight that I will not sit idle in my chair&amp;#8230; or any chair.]&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/photo-1.jpg&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not talk about 3D printing here, I will talk about a side effect of having a 3D printer at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My children sees the printer as a wonderful toy generator machine&amp;#8230; and I have to recognise that the little people have veritable passion for the plastic moulded stuff: look at their toys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, to the point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday my boy came to me with a list. He was looking at the list and mumbling some words when I asked what was the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/photo-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-200&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/photo-1-225x300.jpg&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;He showed me that list. It was a list of names and words and numbers that made no sense at the beginning&amp;#8230; then he explained his business idea to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m going to sell toys at school, dad&amp;#8230; and this is the list of the people who wants to buy things from me&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the odd list made sense:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the name of a child, the name of the toys and the price they had to pay for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m going to get rich selling toys, dad&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smiled and asked him if he had considered how much it cost to produce the toys and he looked at me puzzled:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s free, dad!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Well, the fact that you don&amp;#8217;t pay anything it doesn&amp;#8217;t mean it&amp;#8217;s free&amp;#8221; (my mind drifted to all this web services that were supposedly free in exchange of &amp;#8220;some&amp;#8221; of your data&amp;#8230;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/minion.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-205&#34; alt=&#34;minion&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/minion-300x225.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to explain to him how he could calculate and how much he should charge for every toy&amp;#8230; I could see he lost interest quickly &amp;#8220;makes no sense, dad&amp;#8230; I cannot put a different price to any toy, I will need two lists, one for my toys and one for the children&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed you will need, my dear&amp;#8230; That&amp;#8217;s exactly how shops all over the world work. You have a list with stock and prices and a list of customers&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversation moved on and we left the little toy factory aside but when I went to bed I told my wife &amp;#8220;darling, I&amp;#8217;m afraid we&amp;#8217;re breeding Entrepreneurs&amp;#8221; and last night, last night I slept well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardware Week</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/08/19/hardware-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/08/19/hardware-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This last week has been a bit crazy with all the new stuff that is going on but&amp;#8230; if last week was mayhem, get ready because this week is hardware week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I will go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://london.hackspace.org.uk/&#34;&gt;London Hackspace&lt;/a&gt;  to see what do they do and &lt;strong&gt;IF&lt;/strong&gt; it would make any sense to join them. I will unveil an idea that I&amp;#8217;ve been working on for the last weeks. One of the things that I&amp;#8217;ve learnt during these last 2 years is that no idea is good if no money can be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree that making money is &amp;#8220;the business part&amp;#8221; of the idea and I&amp;#8217;ve been tempted to write a post about that in reply to a conversation that was triggered in Twitter by the fine people of Klicap. However, time is precious and &amp;#8220;Talking is easy&amp;#8221; so, my new motto is &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Make More, Talk Less&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; (not that this many people are listening).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super exciting times where I have to deal with Software and Hardware and the close relationship between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pre-holidays week is all about hardware:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rapsberry Pis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NFC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And :blibb that we could say it&amp;#8217;s the glue that ties them together. As I said&amp;#8230; Exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startups Españolas, This is London Calling</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/27/startups-espanolas-this-is-london-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/27/startups-espanolas-this-is-london-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hace un tiempo tuve la idea de organizar un evento de programadores para programadores. Lo llame 8Dev y se suponía que iba a organizarse en Mallorca. La idea era simple, coger 8 programadores de puta madre de por aquí, meterlos en un avión y que explicaran lo que hacían a los programadores españoles. Incluso llegamos a hablar con &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Klaus_Knopper&#34;&gt;Klaus Knopper&lt;/a&gt; para que asistiera, y si no recuerdo mal, hasta conseguimos un par de sponsors (uno era Microsoft, a la que no le hacía mucha gracia el tema Knopper, pero aún así dijo que contaramos con ellos). Hablamos con Atlassian para ver si se subirían al carro pero al final todo se derrumbó.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizar algo en España cuando vives en Londres es, por ponerlo en una palabra, complicado. Pero tal vez lo que más me sorprendió fue la actitud de muchos de los programadores a los que les pregunté qué le parecía un evento así&amp;#8230; pero eso, como dice &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bonillaware.com/&#34;&gt;el Bonilla&lt;/a&gt;, es otra historia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recientemente mande un tweet sobre organizar un Spanish Day en el Google Campus y para gran sorpresa mía, varias personas no sólo respondieron sinó que me ofrecieron su ayuda y yo, desde aquí, os lo agradezco enormemente.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuve una breve charla con &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ediggs&#34;&gt;Eze Vidra&lt;/a&gt;, Head of Google Campus, y la idea de organizar un evento con Startups españolas le pareció genial!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidentemente yo, siendo yo, me puse a pensar en lo que se podría organizar y fue en ese momento que me di cuenta que a lo mejor el tal Ries tenía razón y deberia echar el freno y (releerme el capítulo de su libro sobre MVPs) y un cafe y medio después y varios folios garabateados llegué a la conclusión que lo mejor era preguntarle aquí al respetable si les interesaría.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eze sólo dijo que oranizaramos lo que organicemos se ha de pensar en el aforo, así que aquí lanzo mi pregunta:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¿Startups españolas, os interesaría participar en un evento en el Google Campus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si la respuesta es sí, poneros en contacto conmigo ya sea mediante mi &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ipedrazas&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, o un emilio  de toda la vida (ivan at este dominio) o incluso un simple comentario.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Project Managers should have children</title>
      <link>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/19/why-project-managers-should-have-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.pedrazas.me/2013/02/19/why-project-managers-should-have-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I&amp;#8217;m out with my children people makes comments about how busy we must be with three little monsters. Yes, we are&amp;#8230; but there&amp;#8217;s nothing you cannot solve with a bit of organisation, loads of patience and chocolate. Bribing is a must!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/ID-10081433.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-44&#34; alt=&#34;ID-10081433&#34; src=&#34;http://ivan.pedrazas.me/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/ID-10081433-300x223.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;223&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;#8217;s a particular case that gest the whole thing wrong: Parents with only one child. They think that one child takes so much time, that 3 will take at least 3 times more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children, like a team, don&amp;#8217;t add up but mix. It&amp;#8217;s all about how well organised you are and don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong, it&amp;#8217;s not about planning 2 weeks ahead, it&amp;#8217;s about planning what are they going to do next or tomorrow, not in 2 weeks, or summer. Yes, registering for summer camps, like managing training of your team has to be done with plenty of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing software projects and managing children is quite similar. There are very big unknowns. Planning two weeks ahead makes not much sense. Alas, planning what are they going to do after school is never easy because you never know how tired they will be, or which mood they will come out with&amp;#8230; Plan this big dinner to find out that they had this massive Birthday party and they&amp;#8217;ve been fuelled by sugar and noise&amp;#8230; So, yes, you have to plan, planning is key&amp;#8230; as much as being able to be flexible an improvise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How? software development left in hands of improvisation? well, don&amp;#8217;t get me wrong, it&amp;#8217;s not the improvisation that comes with &amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t have a clue&amp;#8230; let&amp;#8217;s try this&amp;#8221; but the improvisation that comes with experience of being now and there. Key is to plan this or that and if it fails (for any reason) do that other thing or try this other approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we are, it&amp;#8217;s not about reading the right books, it&amp;#8217;s about doing the wrong thing and learning from it. Notice the LEARN bit&amp;#8230; any parent with children know their children very well, so when they come home with a foul mood, or tired or XXXX they know how to smooth the transition from school to bed, or how I tell my wife, Bed deployment was success. All unit tests are green, house is quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She text back something along the lines &amp;#8220;nerd! &amp;#8230; love you&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is never easy, but it&amp;#8217;s about being flexible&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>